[Music]
okay
welcome everybody this is
learn dental series
in this episode we will start to discuss
an important topic
in
the field of restorative density which
is
tennis and the treatment planning in
operative entry density
this topic
if you understand it will and apply it
in a perfect manner you will get a good
patient satisfaction about your
treatment and at the same time it will
considered as the cornerstone and
building your repetition in clinical
density career
let me declare that i don't receive fees
compensation or realities from the sales
of any of the products shown or
discussed and also i declare that this
presentation has not been sponsored by
any company agency or organization
it is only prepared for educational
purposes
please
this presentation is copyright protected
and holds this in your mind okay could
not be reproduced
by or transmitted by any mean without
prayer permission of the author by the
end of this presentation you are
expected to be able to record patient
data and realize it's important okay
and the record patient chief complain
and analyze its history correlate
between medical and dental history and
the proposed treatment plan
then in the coming episodes we will
discuss how to correlate between the
order and dental clinical findings and
the proposed treatment plan properly
diagnose dental care is especially by
different techniques
including all updated
techniques and maneuvers to discover
early lesions
also properly diagnose and evaluate any
existing restoration and design a proper
restorative treatment plan in a good
interdisciplinary
rational with other speciality
our topic
is classified into three main parts
after introduction part one is the
patient assessment and the information
gathering we will discuss demographic
data chief complain medical history
dental
then comes
the
most important part is the clinical
examination and diagnosis including
examination of dental care as it is our
specialty followed by examination of
existing restoration okay also
included in our speciality and becomes
examination of other two defects related
to restorative and operative density and
what are the adjunctive aids for
examining teeth and restorations
examining the occlusion examining
patient in vain and examining cracked
tools then comes the final part based on
the information gathered from
patient assessment and clinical
examination including treatment plans
okay
we will discuss the prognosis of each
case and how to
define or trying to assign
the prognosis of each case followed by
how to design our treatment plan and
what are the interdisciplinary
concentrations let us start our journey
and we would like to clarify that
diagnosis
is the art of identification or
recognition observation problem okay why
it is an art okay it's art based on
science as we always say in art and
science okay it's art but based on
science art because it needs a
perfection
of
experience of
gained experience and perfectly applied
okay to loses the operator should have
interest intuition curiosity but all of
these means that you are in hurry all
with interest inclusion curiosity if we
describe any a person by these
characters it means that it may be in
hurry but at the same time when you are
diagnosis they're losing a patient to
problem
in addition to these three you should be
patient enough to listen and to take
your time to discover the patient
problem
then you should have a sense
a sense trying to guess okay
where is the truth
did the patient tell a lie all the
division tell the truth okay
this are an important characters which
are grown
by experience by skills by bragging
remember all those practice makes
perfect okay that's why our diagnostic
procedures
only includes two major
steps or two major category okay
categories
first one patient assessment and
information gathering
just a chat with the patient
just
you are talking and debating with each
other okay trying to reach to the truth
okay
after you finish your patient assessment
and the information gathering okay
just use your clinic critical thinking
skills that will direct you
in
a speciality definite specialty
direction and density
let us say okay
when a patient
say that he is suffering from severe
pain and he pointed out a tooth what
comes in my mind
is
if i am a general practitioner
this case is in between
hindu and surgery
okay either pulp excellation of
extraction of the tooth
if he is suffering from
a throbbing pain and continuous
okay and a little bit swelling
then
there is an infection as if there is a
sort of infection
my mind comes to either peru
and at the same time surgery but when
your patient is coming to you
asking
or
demanding
uh to improve his anterior or
entirety's
aesthetics or demanding for
improving his smile then you go for
either
respiration density or fixed prosthetics
all now is under the umbrella of what is
called ascetic density
okay and so on that's why it is
important to listen to your patient this
it is a
much
it is
an important topic to take your time in
patient assessment and information
gathering that will guide you what's the
direction you will go forward for the
proper treatment of such a case and at
the same time
you could assign
the type of your patient you could
assign
uh what are the problems uh
your patient faced or complications your
patient faced before
when he had done any previous mental
treatments and so on then comes the
clinical examination
okay
clinical examination you ask the patient
to sit on your dental chair okay trying
to confirm what your mind map
designed
to go forward
what you think about the case
either it is between hindu or extraction
then you're ready you know that there is
an acute problem but what direction will
go forward either direction of advantage
or direction of extraction this will be
confirmed by your clinical examination
that's why you should start with your
patient assessment
and the information gathering without
patient assessment and the information
gathering clinical examination
will be like amaze
okay you will it's a puzzle you don't
know what instrument you should start
with
you don't know how to discover the
patient problem
that's why patient assessment and
information gathering if you consider
this
as a time wasting technique but also
it's a time saving much more time saving
you will gain when you go for clinical
examination a few
uh take your time for patient assessment
and the information gathering before
seating your patient on the dental chair
okay let us start with this topic
patient assessment and information
gathering starting with
demographic data okay what are the
demographic dev test normal data of each
person including name okay
why
i should know the patient name okay
it's not only a documentation procedure
that each file you open should have the
patient name and
full name including family name
including the first one the middle
uh and the family name no but also
ethically
when you are calling your patient in his
name this adds a more ethical
communication okay
if you
add his name
like mr
ex mr wall mr zed okay this adds a more
respect and a more ethical communication
that will relieve the tension and stress
of your patient and at the same time
he will discover that you are keen and
interested to know his problem and solve
that
number two comes the address okay why
should i know where my patient lives or
where
where did he come from okay
because
at this era
we already fighting the pandemic of
covent 19 okay
when you know the area your patient come
from you will get an information about
the epidemic infectious state
of this area suppose this area okay
is known by epidemic infections okay
then you will not refuse or reject to
treat this patient but at least you take
certain precautions or special
precautions to prevent further
cross-infection according to
the schematic chart of epidemic charts
that one patient could infect the three
each one of them could infect another
three then one patient could result in
mind infections like new infections and
so on okay multiplied by three every
time
this is number one
number two it reflects patient
availability and the frequency of
treatment appointments okay because in
our
specialty restorative density sometimes
as we discussed in previous episodes
that we are in need for go-to to go to
for indirect restorations and direct
restoration will not be finished in
single visit it needs at least two to
three visits okay then according to
the address of your patient
and
the frequency of treatment appointment
appointments i could design
how to solve the patient problem
is this case is available and this
patient having the luxury to come to us
multiple visits or it is difficult to
him then i should refer him to another
colleague or i should shift to another
suitable restorative management that's
why we should know the others in other
countries and this addresses and
important to send bills
okay and he should pay for you okay you
should send bills for him
to know
uh to get your money okay or what is the
insurance nearest insurance company to
cover this treatment
followed by
what about the age
why you should record the age
all our patients in restorative density
and mature okay enough we are not
dealing with
young kids okay we are not dealing with
primary teeth we are dealing with
permanent ease of mature adults okay but
the word mature adults
it ranged from
okay up to
100 200 whatever
okay the patient age okay but
our range is very wide starting from 18
okay
this means that the size
of the bulb chamber
and your lesion approximation and your
preparation approximation to the valve
chamber
differs as the patient gets
older
that means that your bulb
gets much more recessed
okay and get much more far away
from your legion or your
cavity design that's why you are need to
know the age to estimate
the tips of the gravity and biological
principles to be followed
you are need to estimate the position of
the gingival attachment is
it in normal position normal
physiological position or the patient
i may expect gingival recession also the
condition of calcified tooth structure
is there any attrition or not is there
any intense healthy roses or not and
also the selection of restorative
material and technique
as long as your patient gets
older okay you always
try to select
direct restorations
it tends to be much more
metallic okay in bostiritis rather than
ascetic unless the case is indicated for
bonded restoration but ascetic is not
our prime concern now okay he needs a
strong durable restoration regardless
attacks okay except if it is in the
anterior area if your vision
is
toward
a younger zone
from 18 say up to
40 okay then your choices
are always related to aesthetics they as
they get younger they prefer ascetic and
they get older they prefer functionality
they preferred
how long
it will be successful regardless the
asset
then comes
six
okay
and here i would like to clarify
something that is
uh
filing systems
and dental practice
systems okay
prefer to write it as ginder not sex no
ginder is an attitude it's a personal
attitude okay but
six
is a physiology
and the anatomical term related to
the body
okay related to
the body physiology
which is the most important for me not
the attitude of the patient he prefers
to be toward
feminine or masculine character okay or
anything in between it's related to his
attitude and behavior and his preference
but six is a terminology describing
the body anatomy and physiology
also the hormonal pattern of zapati and
what is
an expected
condition
medical condition or physiological
conditions that may
be related to my treatment plan that's
why we already determined it six six
either male or a female okay
why i should report sex
i already okay see my patient by naked
eye and i could
write down uh
it's it's a
h6 okay
but now a day is number one you have
kinder transformations or sex
transformations okay in certain
countries not in our
arab countries it is not common okay but
it is common in other countries and
other cultures okay that's why he may
appear appear his appearance
uh like a male and he is physiologically
a female and vice versa okay this is
number one okay
number two because there is
certain names okay could be for a man or
for a woman
okay that's why if any colleague
try to review the patient file or when i
referred it to the
other colleague for any consultation he
should know the sex of your patient okay
and the name first name is not
indicative for six okay at the same time
some uh
systems okay
uh gets on these initials not the full
name okay that's why you should write
down what's the six of your patient okay
then
what is most important is
in our treatment plan this is
administrative work but what about the
clinical parts a clinical part in our
treatment plan certain diseases are
related to specific
sex
like
oral conditions related to pregnancy for
female only
okay
like gingival enlargement during
pregnancy and administration
bilateral erosion as you could see in
our
photographs the next photograph okay
which is uh
due to regulation of gastric uptake and
hyper acidity during pregnancy
especially if it is frequently pregnancy
uh without any period of thrust in
between each pregnancy and the other
okay
local anesthetics and radiographic
limitations for pregnant female okay
selection of restorative material and
technique females always
prefer static rather than metallic
respirations okay
then if you have
a male patient you will not ask him if
he is pregnant or not
okay
but if you have a female patient you
should ask the next question if she is
pregnant or not and if she is pregnant
in which trimester she is in okay
because of local anesthetics and
radiographs but actually if you have a
male patient okay you will not ask him
about these conditions okay this is
uh clinical photographs for the
left side showing pregnancy gingivites
okay that will much more advance it in
the right one to be gingival polyp okay
due to lack of proper care during
pregnancy of parliamental hills okay
in such a case if you have a cares okay
in between
the two is a central and the lateral
like this one in the left side okay if
you notice
there is a clustery
mesial glassy compositoris illustration
in the mesial surface of lateral incisor
tooth okay but you could note
a marginal discoloration because your
operator after finishing
this
restoration discovered this line because
he didn't consider the pregnancy
gingivitis and bleeding
from the gingiva contaminated the
margins
okay that's why he should refer the case
for peruntus first to manage the case
and the berlinest may refer the case for
an ecologist okay to manage these
pregnancy gingivites before we start our
restorative management then comes
patient accumulation
patient occupation
why you are in need to know the patient
incubation number one it provides an
idea about certain incubation and
defects
like the one you could see tooth where
that
had taken the shape okay of
a bin
okay
because this patient is working as a
dress maker okay or a fashion designer
something and they used pins okay well
over 20 years put it in between his
holding it in between his incisors okay
then it wears the tools okay leaving
these notches okay the same for
carpenters if you would like to restore
this with
a composite resin restoration okay this
is what you could get in your mind
immediately okay but actually you could
note that okay
his point and his occlusion is shifted
to be edge to edge he is trying to hold
the balance in between his centrals this
is number one okay
and still there is a force applied
on the side of the legion
then you have it looks very simple just
beveling and butting
or packing compositories no it's not
that simple as you could imagine because
already the patient bite is edge to edge
at the same time not only is the force
applied from edge to edge occlusion but
also
he is holding an external metallic
object between his teeth that will lead
to failure of your restoration and you
will go for dilemma of repeating your
restoration every day and the other
every day and the other every day and
other okay unless you correct this
condition okay that's why you should get
an enough information about the patient
occupation patient incubation also
determines the degree of interest of the
patient to restorative management the
material and technique of choice and the
time base you will work on your
treatment planning suppose you have a
patient which is uh working as tv
presenter okay and having a daily show
okay a daily live show okay
that means that okay your patient
in such a case could not get out of your
clinic with tf
he should
get out with a completed aesthetic
restoration in a single visit
okay
at the same time
minimal intervention okay should be
applied why minimal intervention should
be applied minimal intervention it
doesn't mean here that you need a very
conservative cavity because minimal
intervention and the conservative crafty
there are other factors that controls
how to apply it okay
including the lesion itself okay its
extension
its severity its activity blah blah blah
but here i mean that minimal
intervention that the shortest treatment
okay with laser complication until you
arrange enough time with your patient
okay to do that that's why you should
know
the expression occupation
but
let us go for
the most important issue
comes
after demographic data
immediately is the chief complaint what
does the chief complain okay the chief
complaint it is defined that the main
problem that
drives
drives him like a car okay
drives him mandatory and that really
okay
to go for dental clinic this is the main
problem that drives a patient to dental
clinic by asking him what's your problem
and it should be recorded in patient's
own words
don't translate it to
dental terminology
write it down or record it down as a
patient okay till you because is the one
suffering and he's the one
who could exactly describe the condition
okay
in the field of density especially when
you are
a general practitioner
okay
we may have
hundreds of complaints different ways
described different severities okay
according to the patient character
what's the problem and the patient
character patient age okay psychological
impact of the problem on your patients
okay but
four of them
when recorded by your patient
then operative density
jump to your mind
okay that's why uh when we start our
talk we mentioned that it is important
to listen okay listen to the patient and
take your time in patient assessment
because it it draws a road map
for your critical thinking where you
should go forward for treating this
patient okay
number one
okay
food stagnation and the impaction
food stagnation and infections that
means that there is a cavitation
this cavitation okay or this space
okay maybe due to
uh
thief crowding
maybe due to cares
especially proximal area okay and the
patient couldn't see it or couldn't
expect it by his necked eye maybe due to
periodontal problems like like
horizontal pockets okay
but operative density
proximal cares should jump to your mind
okay
if he
complaining directly and frankly from
cavitation or fracture
okay
then
even it is associated with pain or not
the problem is between objective and
endo okay
discoloration
the same okay
is it
due to chaos
is it due to other defects like
fluorosis okay is it just a
discoloration due to smoking or due to
over intake of coffee or tea okay and
needs just polishing or just bleaching
then comes the worst condition is
sensitivity or pain
okay
that denotes it is something abnormal
okay as the vein is defined as and in
the topic of
pain and hypersensitivity it's unblazing
sensation denoting degree of tissue
damage okay
but
this is not the whole story okay just
your patient is telling you that i'm
having a side with food stagnation or
i'm having cavitation or i'm having pain
or i'm having discoloration
no
you should ask for each of these
complaints for more details which is
called history which you've complained
it's a very very very important
task to perform before you are going for
clinical examination ask about the
history of the chief complaint because
it will help you to
locate
your problem where it is established
okay the nature quality and the urgency
of the problem is defined by the history
still up till now you didn't ask your
patient to come to see it on dental
chair okay
it also encourages salvation
to volunteer additional information that
will complete the picture all the verbal
picture of the problem okay and also
also psychologically
it adds
a much trust and a much confidence
between you and your patient as he will
realize that you are interested to know
his problem to solve it
okay you are keen about him you are
trying to solve his problems that's why
you get at the much more details like a
detective
okay
you should ask
about
commencement
okay
when did it start okay either it is food
stagnation either it is vain either it
is discoloration when the first time he
noticed it or the first time he is
complaining from it okay location let
the patient describe the area or point
out the area with the finger okay
in general if he pointed out a tooth
okay it's different than pointing out
area okay if he pointing out a tooth
this means that your pain or your
problem is affecting pressure receptors
that may indicate
peripheral or periodontal
condition
or the extent of the damage okay reaches
up to the peripheral or supplemental
condition
or the peripheral and the productive
condition are sharing
with your main problem
but
if he couldn't point out a definite
tools and pointed out an area
okay including two to three teeth or a
whole quadrant then but it is
much more aggressive
on uh toward a tooth rather than the
other then you have a referral pain okay
in such a condition
this indicates that your problem
is affecting a sensory receptors
okay sensor receptors are mainly
in the bulb
okay pulp contains
much more sensory receptors than other
dental tissues that's why you could
expect bulbal affection okay and your
condition is still limited to
uh
cistus
which you could find it by a clinical
examination then comes the type
description of the symptoms
okay
what's the type
is it aching
is it throbbing is it lancinating but
please
don't direct your patient
by putting words
in the patient mouse
okay don't ask him
is it
throbbing yes or no
okay
is it clancinating i think it is
fantastic
those are bad management
in
your discussion with your patient let
him describe ask him to describe the
pain
okay or to describe the problem don't
give him a clue to describe it
okay
because actually
the patient
already knows that you are a specialist
in this field you are the dentist and
you knows much more than him that's why
he will agree with your choice
okay he will think that you know it is
actually throbbing okay then you are
right and i am wrong
while it is not the truth it is not the
actual condition okay then number four
ask about the incidence how long
ago
did this episode start
okay
for how long for
uh did it started last year then to stop
and then comes again after one month
like this okay duration
for how long do they persist and the
frequency okay is it a continuous pain
okay always we uh
go for brain as an example because it is
uh one of the most complicated uh chief
complaints in its history okay but this
applies for all other
chief complaints in a way or another
okay
then
is it a continuous pain
is it intermittent pain if it is
intermittent what is the frequency
between each episode okay
initiating and relieving factors
does
anything make the symptoms worse or
better okay
most of patients reported that okay i
take many analgesics okay but
this is still annoying me
if you correlate this with a type of
pain and duration you will discover
surely it is a throbbing pain okay
continuous
but it is of low intensity this means
that you have a chronic infection okay
that starts to be accelerated as acute
one okay and that's why analgesics was
not effective
some patients in some countries okay
could get a desktop uh
antibiotics okay in
many countries including our country
egypt okay and most of our boards uh
antibiotics are available to be sailed
without prescription okay then your
patient may get antibiotics and he
mentioned to you that okay the brain is
relieved after antibiotic then you could
expect that there is an infection that's
why it is responding to antibiotics
okay
answers of all the abuse
will provide you with much more close
clues
to soul patient problem as i told you
before okay it will
draw your mind map
okay and it will guide your critical
thinking to solve the problem and to
limit your search okay and to reach a
definite
diagnosis okay that's why
we always
hurry to skip the history and jump to
tools
consequently
we may miss the definite diagnosis of
patient problem and the treatment plan
may not fit too much it that's why
please please please listen to
understand not to reply okay you are not
listening to your patient okay to reply
to his
uh
inquiries no
you are in need to listen
to understand the problem and solve it
then comes the medical history
before examination and diagnosis
and sometimes in the reception patient
complete a standard comprehensive
medical history form as a checklist yes
or no
the form
will act as a focus
to the practitioner to help identify the
condition that could later complicate or
contraindicate some dental procedures
okay
that's why
to have
a medical history form
just to save your time okay and ask the
patient during your assessment or during
the interview with the patient about any
yeses
okay
or gets
focused on what is yes and what is new
to make sure about the medical condition
of the patient why you should have a
report about medical or systemic
condition observation is there any
contraindication of restorative
treatment no as a general goal there is
no systemic contraindication to
restorative treatment
except those of uncontrolled diabetes
or a recent of history of myocardial
infarction and also
those two conditions are temporary
contraindicated unless
it is
until it is fixed or solved or be
controlled okay
because we are afraid of local
anesthesia okay
till it will be controlled
that's it okay
we are not in hurry
an operative density
emergencies are
extremely limited
okay unless uh as a case it should be
referred for in do not
but for restorative management for
operative management
uh mostly our
pain
in maximum it will be just a sensitivity
not pain when it becomes to be a sharp
pain then you are a need to refer the
case for endodontist that's why we are
not in hurry we are not in emergency
okay that's why
please take your medical history you
could solve the patient problem
temporarily by excavating the carriers
and the botting sedative tf until he
controls his good medical condition
condition to be in safe side okay
and avoid complications of local
anesthesia
some cases
patient may require antibiotic
prophylaxis before starting dental
treatment and also excavator hairs and
sedates the condition and seal it with
tf okay because of systemic conditions
like prosthetic valve histogrammatic
fever cancer chemo or radiotherapy okay
you need to work under umbrella of
antibiotic
prophylaxis okay
in contralateral to this or on
controversy to these patients with
infectious disease then
either you are afraid of
observation to get infected okay or
afraid
of infection okay to the patient or from
the patient patients with infectious
diseases
okay
ethically you could not reject him you
could not refuse him just follow your
protection protocol that's it okay
in certain cases there's a need for a
special protocol okay and special
precautions especially nowadays we have
the pandemic of coffin 19 okay the
endemic of covenant 19 okay the personal
protective barrier and the infection
control protocol already
get upside down and change it and it
is restricted protocol to follow okay
that covers
most of
highly infectious dangerous diseases
okay including hepatitis herbs and
syphilis tb all of these okay i have the
right
to be
treated
but you should follow the recommended
special infection control protocol
that's it okay how you know this if you
didn't ask about medical history okay
also you are need to know the medical
security how to avoid adversity
interactions if the patient is under
medication
okay and you are need to subscribe or
describe to him an antibiotic or
analgesic you should make sure of the
medical condition observation to avoid
drug interactions adverse drugs and drug
interactions okay even if it is a
sensitivity okay from antibiotics or
allergy from energetics or stomach
problem that grt problems that
contraindicate certain analgesics and so
on okay
some conditions
medical conditions may contra-indicate
techniques or devices or equipment used
in dental treatment
like patients with base maker
it is not preferable at all to use
electric bulb tester
okay that may interfere with the
frequency of
the space maker okay
the problem is
all of these conditions as we discussed
now
is a patient knowing what he is
suffering
from
okay is he as is he having a systemic
problem or he is a chronic patient who
is
compromised patient with a simple
problem but
majority of people some patients
are aware of their systemic condition
and
majority of others are not aware that
you are they are having a systemic
problem
that's why
your questionnaire or your medical
history form
should not only include a definite
medical terminology
okay
you should ask him about
other open-ended questions okay about
unexplained weight loss
unexplained hair loss
about
any articaria to food okay
any
skin reactions okay
to certain drugs
okay
your patient may
get this experience once alive
but he considered it okay as normal but
sometimes it may reflect something
abnormal okay
ask him about urination
okay frequent urination okay that may
indicate diabetes okay all of these
should be asked and already you could
get thousands or millions of
history forms okay uh approved by uh
[Music]
iconic organizations okay online for
free okay it's easy to get it okay
the technique
most of the people followed okay
as a formatted checklist in a form of
yes or no asking mostly about cardiac
problem or disease including rheumatic
fever blood pressure including also
respiratory diseases asthma shortness of
breath and nowadays we could add okay a
cover 19 experience
okay it should be added okay diabetes
epilepsy june sabotage
current recent past medication allergies
bleeding hemorrhage clotting defects
okay other illness operations
hospitalization pregnancy but pregnancy
is not a medical condition it's a
physiological condition and timbre
[Music]
medical
condition hiv aids communicable disease
risk like that
scully and the calcium
okay
give checklist for medical conditions
that
should be reviewed and need special care
and arrange it in alphabetical manner
in order to
remember it uh easily a b c d up to n
okay anemia bleeding disorder
cardiovascular cardio respiratory
disorder drug treatment and allergies
endocrine diseases that are those are
the categories okay uh you should ask
definite quiz definite questions
underneath okay direct treatment
allergies endocrine diseases including
diabetes thyroid and
blah blah blah fats and veins
gastrointestinal disorders hospital
admission infection ruined this kidney
likelihood pregnancy or pregnancy mental
state neurologic problems this are those
are described by scully and the calcium
in
2014 okay
the last
important item in patient assessment and
information gathering is the dental
history okay
the mental history it refers to
what a dental treatment your patient
okay
uh have done before because it provide
you an idea about the degree of interest
of your patient and also it gives you an
idea about what is expected to be seen
in his mouth let me give you an example
if you ask the patient did you
go for a dentist before or what type of
treatment you have done in your teeth
you will say to you i always wait until
my tooth is damaged and i would like
also i prefer to extract it
okay
then you are expecting
to see a miss mouse with mouse
okay
i am expecting to see remaining roots i
am expecting to see badly broken down
tools or at least if it is not the
condition since the patient is not
interested in any dental treatment okay
then i should prepare myself that i will
suffer in convincing him in restorative
treatment or much more
conservative and less aggressive or less
traumatized treatment than extraction
okay
that's why okay
it gives you an idea about the degree of
interest and what is expected to be seen
in his mouse also gives you an idea
about the expected complications and
what is the reason behind these
complications let us say
he suffered from
[Music]
swelling and
him at home underneath the skin after
skin after he had administrated
with local anesthesia okay
then
is it an allergy is it a sensitivity
reaction to local anesthesia or it may
be
an uh heterogenic
mistake from
the previous dentist okay i should know
what is the problem okay what is the
circumstances and the conditions are
around this problem to
know how to avoid
okay
and how to
give the patient okay painless dental
care okay including also bleeding after
extractions or after surgeries or after
brudental therapy why he didn't continue
his treatment what is his problem okay
to get much more
trust between us okay
that's why it is important to understand
past experience in order to provide
optimal care in the future
those are the textbook
i
used in preparing this presentation uh
if you would like to get much more
information you could go for them please
feel free to ask as your questions are
welcome every time you could ask or
question by commenting to this video
and they will reply to you as soon as
possible or use my email in the coming
slide to ask me and i will reply also as
soon as possible
finally i would like to thank you for
assigning this time to listen to me
please don't forget to subscribe to my
channel and activate notification to get
all the updates thank you yes
if